eight months
15 videos and 10 000 kilometers later
i finally have a scratch on my car
and what hurts the most is it isn't
because of something i did it was a hate
crime
the irony of it all this happened
immediately after our last video where
we showcased compass in all its glory
it's a goddamn key scratch all the way
from the front panel to the rear door
why the hell would somebody do that
so anyway i contacted my car detailer
who is detailing mafia and i told him
this is the situation this is the
problem what is the solution i have
he said sir the entire car could be
rebuffed
but
it will cost you 8 000 plus gst now that
is just too much
the next option was i went to the
showroom and i
asked him what are the solutions i have
he said sir you have two options one is
you can claim insurance and get it done
for free or the second option is without
claiming insurance you can repaint the
panels
now repainting three panels is too
expensive it costs me
9500 per panel
that's 25 000 bucks that's just
ridiculous
so i opted to claim insurance and that
my friends is the topic of this video
how to claim insurance and what are the
steps involved
so i have an insurance from icici
lombard
i contacted the customer care the number
which will be mentioned in your policy
and the representative asks you for a
few particulars your personal
particulars your vehicle details and
most importantly a brief description of
the incident
so you give a brief description and
summarize the incident and the
conclusion of the call they'll give you
a claim number now this is very
important because all your further
correspondence is in regard to this
claim number
so what you do is if you have a physical
claim form you fill your personal
particulars you fill your vehicle
particulars and you fill the claim
number
and then you hand over the claim form to
your
respective garage
following the conversation and once you
register with the customer care
your next step is
and survey
now to do a survey there are two options
either the online survey or the offline
server
now the offline survey will take 24
hours where they send the surveyor
directly to your doorstep i chose the
online server now in online survey what
happens is
you download the i and take care app and
you navigate through the app you land on
a page where there is online survey this
is very convenient because it's
basically a video call and the surveyor
will guide you on what to show and he'll
ask you a bit about the incident
so first you show all four sides of the
card you show the odometer reading and
you show the win number once the survey
is complete
then you hand over the car to the garage
and that is where i'm going right now
so i don't know if you guys can see this
but this is the scratch
i'll show you guys yeah this is the
scratch and this scratch is there all
the way till the end
so right now i've just made it to the
service center i think there are like
two or three more steps left before i
hand over the car once i hand over the
car i'll just brief you guys of what
exactly is the process
see i think here it is clear
yeah this
and see there's a dent here as well see
so i don't know what exactly that person
had in mind when he did this but
hopefully everything gets covered in
insurance and i'll keep you guys updated
on what the next steps are
do
[Music]
so here i am guys i've just filled out
the form as of now they have given me a
cost estimate process is once you get a
cost estimate then afterwards you have
to send it to the surveyor and they will
give you something called a work order
so once the insurance company approves
the claim then you they will give you
something as a work order and once the
showroom people receive the work orders
when the work commences
so this as you guys can see it cost so
it is something around 27.945 plus taxes
this is for repainting three panels i'm
not even kidding for three panels it's
so much so right now they've given this
repair estimation to the insurance guys
and once they approve it they will send
something called work order and that is
when jeep commences hey guys so i'm in
the cab right now heading back i've just
dropped the vehicle the time right now
is one six three zero i reached here at
one four zero zero so it taken me two
and a half hours to finally get the work
order
so once the work order has come they
have given me an invoice of 32 000 that
is all the parts labor and taxes
included i've handed the vehicle over to
them they have said that they will hand
over the vehicle to me in another two
days
but then again that is subject to if the
work has been done correctly or not
[Music]
so that is it guys all the steps
involved first call up the customer care
next do the online survey or the offline
survey third is submit your claim form
and fourth is the showroom or the garage
will send a repair estimate form to the
insurance company and finally the
insurance company will send you the work
permit or the work order and once the
showroom receives the work order then
they commence the work that is all that
it is there's nothing more to it
[Music]
[Applause]
so hey guys i'm finally here at the
service center and i've come to collect
the car problem that i faced today is
while they were repainting the panels
the prior step is to prepare the surface
and while they were preparing the
surface they have not prepared it
cleanly and they have painted over the
dust particles now because of which
there is a lot of pit stains on the car
so i am not able to do anything about it
the only solution is to repaint it but
they will repaint it at no extra cost
which is covered by the insurance but
since i need the car right now i am
taking the car along with me and i will
be giving back the car to them in
another 5 000 kilometers because my
first service is due so when i give my
car for first service i've told them
that i needed to be repainted and
whatever repainting had to be done i'm
going to tell them to do it then so i've
taken it in writing from them i know i
hope you guys can see this
yeah so i've taken it in writing from
them that
we'll do repainting for the doors which
are done now at your first service
kindly please support us as approved by
gm
whoever it is
whatever the deals or waivers or claims
that you have with the service center
people always take it in writing that is
the advice i would like to get you guys
and also one more thing i need to tell
you guys which i did not know prior to
this insurance claim is
not everything is covered within the
insurance claim so it right now a
compulsory deductible or processing
charge of 2 000 rupees has been deducted
as in i have to pay out of my pocket and
also an extra fitment charge and washing
charges
so the overall total has come up with
3552 which i had to pay out of my pocket
so i don't know if you guys were living
in this bubble that everything is
covered under insurance it is not okay
so that is the bad news
and now let's go check out the car
so you can see this was where the
scratch was right
but now they have repainted all the
three panels
a small issue that is there is this spit
stains which you can see here
right
so these pit stains will they are going
to deal with these pit stains when i
give it for first servicing at 15 000
kilometers and that time they'll be
repainting the panels but other than
that i think the car looks good
and that is the entire insurance claim
process and i've told you guys all the
steps involved
and that is it if you guys have any
questions please feel free to mention it
in the comments and i'll do my best to
answer whatever queries you have don't
forget to subscribe to the channel where
i try to keep you guys informed on
whatever i learn in life well this as
you guys saw was a new experience for me
as well the first time in my entire life
i've claimed insurance
and so i just thought there'll be a lot
of people out there like me who don't
know what the process for insurance
claim is and i just wanted to enlighten
you guys
and if you like this video if you found
it informative please do hit that like
button show your support to the channel
encourage us to put out more of such
content
and as always i'll see you on next
week's adventure guys see you